

Austin, TX | (512) 903-2690 | handalib@utexas.edu | www.hesamandalib.com

SUMMARY

Experienced designer and project manager with a passion for **learning and applying new technologies** with the purpose of **making life more enjoyable** for everyone. Highly interested in experiencing projects **from concept to implementation**. Able to **generate ideas from abstract problems** and **designing prototypes, testing and directing** them to the production phase.

EXPERIENCE

Service Designer

University of Texas at Austin / Texas Digital Library 2019 — Present

- Improved my high-level and abstract design thinking skills in designing a service model for storage and preservation of private and sensitive data in Distributed Digital Preservation networks for the first time in the US.
- Empowered my soft skills by constant communication and collaboration with more than 11 project partners across the US, including UCSD, IMLS, TACC, MARCC, etc.

Designer and Co-founder

CPMC, Iran 2014 - 2018

 Successfully established and managed a design-build firm and designed more than 15 projects with high quality in 5 years of practice

Project Engineer

Green Volume Group, Iran 2011-2014

- Increased the work performance of the team 30% by gathering and analyzing site
 data and cutting down unnecessary workloads in design and control of project
 documents
- Empowered my team working skills by working in a mega-project context and within large teams with complex interactions that

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Totell Project

UX design and development / JAN 2019 - Present

- Handling UX/UI design of a project to help people in travel overcome language barriers in restaurants
- Successfully learned and applied MongoDB, Express.js, React.js and Node.js
 --MERN stack -- in less than 3 months for a complex project
 GitHub Link: https://github.com/samandalib/totell

VR Time Machine

VR experience design / SEP 2019 — DEC 2019

 Successfully learned and applied Unity Game Engine and C# programming and deployed a VR experience on Oculus Rift

Hololens App

AR experience design / SEP 2019 — DEC 2019

- Design, develop and usability test of an AR application for working with a poster plotter for people without previous experience.
- Reduced the time of learning to work with the machine for more than 50% comparing with other methods

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin

M.Sc. Information Science 2019 — 2021 Specialization in **HCI and UX/UI Design**

National University of Iran

M.Sc. Project Management 2011 - 2013 Specialization in Project Design Management

Art University of Isfahan, Iran

Bachelor of Architecture 2006 - 2010

SKILLS

UX/UI Design

Wire framing, UX writing, User Journey Mapping, Prototyping, Story boarding, Information Architecture, , Voice UI, UI flows

Research

UX Research, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Competitive Analysis, Contextual Inquiry

Software

Sketch, Figma, Axure, Adobe XD, Framer, JavaScript, Python, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, React.js, Node.js, Photoshop, Illustrator, Autocad, Sketchup, Rhinoceros, Unity, MS Office, MSProject.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Selected Graduation Design Project / 2013Moscow, Russia
International Archiprix exhibition

First Prize Winner / 2011

Connecticut, USA
International Biomimicry Design Competition

First Prize Winner / 2010

Isfahan, Iran National Rural House Architecture Design Competition